Guide to the Harry Weinberger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession, 1915-1943
  - Cheney, Sheldon
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning Sheldon Cheney vs. Simon and Schuster Inc., 1936-1937. In 1929, Cheney submitted to Simon and Schuster a plan for an anthology of plays which they rejected. In 1935, Simon and Schuster published a drama anthology which Cheney claimed followed his plan. Weinberger brought suit against Simon and Schuster. The final decision in the case was against Cheney.
    - Correspondence
      - Ballinger, Hutson, and Bolt (5), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Boni, Albert (3), 1937 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Business Week (1), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Cheney, Mr. and Mrs. Sheldon (36), 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Columbia Law Review (2), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Cushman, Darby, and Cushman (4), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - "Drama: A Golden Treasury" (20) (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Ellner, Charles H. (2), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Fadiman, Clifton
        See: "Drama: A Golden Treasury," box 14, folder 5
      - Gassner, John W.
      - Hill, Frank (1), 1937 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Keiper, Frank (3), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Longmans, Green and Co. (3), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Mantle, Burns
      - Reinheimer, Howard E. (19), 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Rogers, Edward S. (3), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Simon and Schuster (2), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Wright, Jones, and Bronson (2), 1936 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Legal papers, 1936-1937 Mar, undated (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
    - Charts comparing types of anthologies [folder contains cross reference only] (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Charts comparing types of anthologies, Undated (Box 51)
    - Notes (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Ciafolo, Andrea
    The papers consist of letters and notes concerning United States vs. Andrea Ciafalo, 1919. Andrea Ciafalo, an alien, was indicted for failure to register for the draft. Weinberger succeeded in having the indictment dismissed. Ciafalo was then charged with criminal anarchy and the government began deportation proceedings. When Ciafalo failed to appear for examination at Ellis Island, Weinberger resigned as his attorney.
    - Correspondence
      - Ciafolo, Andrea (27), 1919, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Ciafolo, C. (2), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Ciafolo, J. (1), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - New York City Police Department (1), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Pettine and DePasquale (1), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (6), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (15), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Notes (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cisneros, Abraham
    See: Rangel, Jesus M., box 42, folder 19
  - Cline, Charles
    See: Rangel, Jesus M., box 42, folders 20-22
  - Cohen, Maurice
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning New York vs. Maurice Cohen, 1917. Cohen was charged with disturbing the peace by distributing leaflets advertising a mass meeting against conscription. Weinberger served as attorney.
    - Correspondence
      - Cohen, Maurice (6), 1917 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - New York City Magistrates' Court (6), 1917
    - Legal papers, 1917, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - College Entrance Book, Co.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous concerning College Entrance Book Co. vs. McGraw-Hill Book Co. and Augustus H. Smith, 1938-1940. Weinberger, attorney for the plaintiff, charged that Augustus H. Smith's Economics, An Introduction to Fundamental Problems, published by McGraw-Hill, reproduced verbatim many parts of Richard Feier's An Introduction to the Elements of Economic Problems, published and copyright by the College Entrance Book Co. A compromise was reached before the case came to trial.
    - Correspondence
      - Cohen, Theodore (30), 1938-1940 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Conger, Edward A. (1), 1939 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Gerardi, Joseph A.
        See: Cohen, Theodore, box 15, folder 6
      - McGraw-Hill Book Co, Inc. (3), 1940 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Smith, Augustus H. (1), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - White and Case (22), 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Legal papers, 1939 February-1940 February, undated (Box 15, Folder 9-11)
    - Notes (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Collins, Delores L.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning Delores L. Collins vs. Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, 1932-1940. Weinberger was attorney for Delores Lacy Collins (Henderson), widow of test pilot James H. Collins. Mrs. Henderson brought suit against MGM on a charge of infringement of the copyright of the book Test Pilot, written by her late husband. She also charged unfair competition in using the title of the book as the title of a photoplay. The case was tried and dismissed. Weinberger appealled and won a decision awarding the plaintiff monetary compensation.
    - Correspondence
      - A-H, K, L, M-N, P, R-W (90), 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
      - Ash, Thomas (10), 1938 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Collins, Delores L. (Mrs. John Henderson) (37), 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Conroy and Conroy (3), 1938 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Doubleday, Doran and Co. (15), 1936, 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Fitelson and Mayers (38), 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Metro Goldwyn Mayer Picture, Legal department (51), 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - O'Brian, Driscoll, and Raferty (7), 1938-1939 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Rice, Elmer (2), 1939 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - U.S. War Department (7), 1938-1939 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Wagner, John I. (5), 1939-1940 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Whitman, Ransom, Coulman, and Goetz (5), 1938 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Legal papers
      - 1932-1938 September 14 (Box 16, Folder 8-12)
      - 1938 September 15-1940 February (Box 17, Folder 1-10)
      - Undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  - Cooper, Leon
    The papers consist of correspondence concerning New York vs. Leon Cooper, 1917. Cooper was in an auto accident and seriously injured a boy. He retained Weinberger to represent him in the above named action.
    - Cooper, Leon (2), 1917 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Gilbert, B.J. (2), 1917 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Gouverneur Hospital (1), 1917 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Crumit, Frank
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger served as attorney and legal advisor for radio entertainer and singer Crumit. Weinberger represented Crumit in a suit brought by A. F. Ryan who charged Crumit with using some words from her song "Her Old Spanish Shawl" to the tune of Crumit's composition "A Gay Caballero." Weinberger also served as attorney for Crumit in a contract dispute with actor A. E. Matthews. Weinberger advised Crumit on tax matters and on Crumit's attempts to produce a musical play entitled "Great Lady."
    - Correspondence
      - B, C, F-H, K-L, P, S-T, W (40), 1937-1939 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - The American Dramatists (5), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Batten, Barten, Durnstine, and Osborne (10), 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Chaney, Stewart (1), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Chappell and Co. (2), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Crumit, Frank (93), 1937-1940, undated (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
      - Godfrey and Marx (15), 1934, 1937-1939 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Hague, Robert L. (2), 1938 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Harrington, Thomas F. (5), 1938 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Klawans, Bernard (3), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Knight, Al H. (3), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Krakeur, Richard (16), 1938 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Lilly, Edward C. (3), 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Mackey and Herrlich (4), 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Madden, Richard J. (7), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Myers, Robert P. (16), 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - New York State (21), 1937-1939 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Owens, Franklin (27), 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - The Shelley Company (6), 1938-1939, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Shurr, Louis
        See: Krakeur, Richard, box 19, folder 7
      - Stuhler, William R. (4), 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Tompkins, Boal and Tompkins (20), 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Vogel Music Co. (4), 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Wiman, Dwight D. (12), 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Yellenti, Nicholas (2), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Legal papers
      - 1934-1939 (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
      - A) Great Lady, Inc.
        - 1937 April-1939 (Box 19, Folder 16-20)
        - Notes (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - B) Ryan vs. Crumit and Batten, Barton, Durstine and Osborn (BBDO)
        - 1928-1929, 1932, 1938-1940, undated (Box 20, Folder 3-5)
        - Notes and miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Tax materials (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Notes (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Daniel, David S.
    The papers consist of correspondence. Daniel was to be deported because he was deemed likely to become a public charge. Weinberger was to have been attorney in the deportation proceeding, but Daniel died at Ellis Island.
    - Daniel, David S. (7), 1919 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners (1), 1919 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Department of Labor (6), 1919-1920 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - De Boer, Loewe: legal papers, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    The papers consist of legal papers concerning New York vs. Loewe DeBoer, 1917. DeBoer was charged with refusal to enlist and pacifist utterances. He was placed in the Observation Ward of Bellevue Hospital. Weinberger served as attorney.
  - Derkach, Alexander
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Alexander Derkach, Ivan Novikoff, and Leon Bobkin, 1918. Derkach, Novikoff, and Bobkin were charged with criminal anarchy for printing and distributing a pamphlet "Kolokol" (The Bell), which advocated overthrow of the United States Government. Weinberger succeeded in having the case dismissed because the state could not prove that the defendents believed in or taught the ideas advocated in the pamphlet.
    - Correspondence
      - Bobkin, Leon (1), 1918 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Derkach, Alexander (4), 1918 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Liberty Defense Union (2), 1918 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Novikoff, Ivan (7), 1918 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Harold Spielburg Agency (4), 1918 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Legal papers, 1918, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Dorfman, Liebe
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and notes. Dorfman, an alien, was charged with prostitution and held for deportation. Weinberger failed in one attempt to have the warrant cancelled, but eventually the commissioner of immigration of New York cancelled the warrant.
    - Correspondence
      - Aronowitz, Samuel (5), 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Dorfman, Liebe (3), 1921 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Dunn, Ike (3), 1921 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Hennis, H. (1), 1921 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (18), 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Legal papers, 1920 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Eckardt, Harold
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning New York vs. Harold Eckardt, 1916. Eckardt was sentenced to six months in jail for trespassing on a freight train. Weinberger succeeded in having the sentence reduced to three months.
    - Correspondence
      - Eckardt, Eugene H. (4), 1916 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Reitman, Ben L. (3), 1916 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Legal papers, 1916 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Ekerold, Hagbard
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Hagbard Ekerold, 1909-1914. Ekerold refused to let his son be vaccinated. When the boy was denied admittance to school, Ekerold was charged with violating the Compulsory Education Law and fined $5 in the City Magistrates' Court. Weinberger appealed the case three times, but the decision was upheld.
    - Correspondence
      - B-C, H-I, L-N, P, R-T, V-W (34), 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - The Anti-Vaccination League of America (5), 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Ekerold, Hagbard (9), 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Higgins, Charles M. (22), 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Mitchel, John P. (2), 1914 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - National League for Medical Freedom (11), 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - New York State (18), 1912-1914 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Legal papers, 1909, 1911, 1913-1914, undated (Box 21, Folder 7-9)
    - Notes (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Feltman, Emile
    The papers consist of letters concerning United States vs. Emile Feltman, 1920. Feltman, an unregistered alien, was arrested in Arizona because of his activities in the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.) Weinberger, retained by the Workers' Defense Union, argued that deportation proceedings against Feltman should be cancelled due to his service in the Spanish American War. The plea was denied.
    - Feltman, Emile (3), 1920 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth G.
      See: Workers' Defense Union, box 21, folder 12
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (5), 1920 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - U.S. War Department (2), 1920 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Workers' Defense Union (1), 1920 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Feng Shun Exhibition Corporation
    The papers consist of letters, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning the Feng Shun Exhibition Corporation, 1938-1941. Weinberger was attorney for this corporation organized to exhibit Chinese junks at the New York World's Fair and at The Golden Gate International Exhibition. The corporation failed to function and was dissolved.
    - Correspondence
      - Bowman, George A. (1), 1938 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Dodge, Wendell Phillips (6), 1938-1939 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - New York State (9), 1938, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Fernandez, Jose Ramon
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning United States vs. Jose Ramon Fernandez, Rogelio Grecia, Pedro Martin, Jose Micezer, Elario Oretissa, Ramon Sanchez, Placido Santamaria, 1919. Fernandez and the others were charged with criminal anarchy and conspiracy to assasinate President Wilson. Weinberger obtained the release of Oretissa, but the others were deported.
    - Correspondence
      - Grau, Joseph (5), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Martin, Pedro (1), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Sanchez, Raymond (1), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Santamaria, Placido (1), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (8), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Legal papers, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Fernandez, Ramon
    The papers consist of letters. Weinberger was retained by the Workers' Defense Union to defend Fernandez, a member of the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.) and an anarchist. He was deported to Russia.
    - Fernandez, Ramon (3), 1922 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (3), 1922 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers. Weinberger served as legal advisor for his friend M. E. Fitzgerald in re-negotiating a mortgage on her farm.
    - Correspondence
      - Fitzgerald, M. E. (4), 1930 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Frehill, James E. (6), 1930-1931 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Kahn, Otto H. (3), 1931 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Legal papers, 1926, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Flores Magon, Ricardo
    The papers consist of letters, notes, photographs, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Ricardo Flores Magon, 1918-1923. Weinberger attempted to obtain amnesty for Ricardo Flores Magon, who together with his brother Enrique Flores Magon and Librado Rivera, was convicted under the wartime Espionage Law for articles appearing in his periodical Regeneracion. Ricardo Flores Magon was not freed despite Weinberger's repeated insistance that his health was rapidly deteriorating in prison. He died in the United States Penitentiary in Leavenworth in 1920. Interest in this case was widespread throughout the United States and Mexico, due in large part to Weinberger's relentless letter writing. Among those interested in this case were Alice Stone Blackwell, Norman Hapgood, Alvaro Obregon, and Upton Sinclair.
    - Correspondence
      - B, F, I, K, L-N, P, S, W (33), 1920-1923, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (14), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Baldwin, Roger
        See: American Civil Liberties Union, box 22, folder 2
      - Bernal, N. T. (8), 1921-1923 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Blackwell, Alice Stone (29), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Blossom, Frederick A.
        See: Workers' Prison Relief Committee, box 22, folder 22
      - Borah, William E. (3), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Branstetter, Otto (1), 1920 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Browder, Earl R. (1), 1920 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Daugherty, Harry M.
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, Attorney General, box 22, folders 18-19
      - De la Huerta, Adolfo (5), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Fitzgerald, Eleanor M.
        See: League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners, box 22, folder 12
      - Flores Magon, Enrique (10), 1920, 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Flores Magon, Jesus (7), 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Flores Magon, Ricardo (39), 1920-1922 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth G.
        See: Workers' Defense Union, box 22, folder 22
      - Garcia, R. B. (10), 1920, 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Gartz, Kate C. (2), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Haberman, Roberto (5), 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Hapgood, Norman (5), 1921 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Harding, Warren G. (15), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Huddleston, George (5), 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Kansas State Board of Health (4), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Kislusk, Lillian (4), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - LaFollette, Robert M. (2), 1921 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Langworthy, S. B. (9), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Lara, Blas (2), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners (1), 1920 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Morones, Luis N. (6), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Norman, Lucille (30), 1921-1923 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Obrego, Alvaro (5), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Palma, Raul (10), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Ryckman, J.H. (4), 1920-1921 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Sanchez, Andres A. (2), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Sarnoff, Lillie (9), 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Sinclair, Upton (1), 1920 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Taft, Henry W. (2), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Tellez, Manuel C. (16), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Teltsch, Gus (3), 1921 (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - Todd, Helen (4), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Attorney General (48), 1920-1922 (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Pardon Attorney (27), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Superintendent of Prisons (5), 1920, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (11), 1920, 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - U.S. Penitentiary, Leavenworth, Kansas (7), 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - Vasconcelos, Jose (3), 1922 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Workers' Defense Union (1), 1919 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Workers' Prison Relief Committee (3), 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Notes, photographs (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Garcia, Manuel Rey
    The papers consist of letters and notes. Garcia, under the name of Manuel Rey, had been charged along with one hundred members of the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.) with conspiracy to obstruct or violate the Selective Service and Espionage Acts. He was deported to Spain in 1923. He re-entered the United States and was again deported to Spain in 1925 under the name Manuel Rey Garcia.
    - Correspondence
      - American Civil Liberties Union (9), 1925-1926 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Erwin, Charles N. (1), 1925 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth G. (Box 23)
        See: American Civil Liberties Union, box 23, folder 1
      - Garcia, Manuel Ray (3), 1925 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Sarnoff, Lillie (5), 1925 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (13), 1925 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Gendlin, Max
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning United States vs. Max Gendlin, 1920. Gendlin was charged with being an anarchist and held for deportation. Weinberger successfully argued that Gendlin's membership in the Communist Party was insufficient cause for deportation.
    - Correspondence
      - Cloak and suit operators union (7), 1920 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Gendlin, Max (4), 1920 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (4), 1920 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Legal papers, 1920, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - George, Anthony
    The papers consist of letters concerning New York vs. Anthony George, 1917. George ran down and injured Walter Merchant in a car. Merchant retained Weinberger, but any action was postponed because George was arrested to serve a prison term in Atlanta.
    - Correspondence
      - Merchant, Walter (3), 1917 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - New York City District Attorney (2), 1918 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - New York City Police Department (2), 1917 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Glison, George L.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. George L. Glison (Lloyd C. Glison), 1917. Glison was convicted of disorderly conduct tending to a breach of the peace and sentenced to six months in jail. He had distributed anti-Wilson circulars during a patriotic parade. Weinberger was retained by the American Legal Defense League to defend Glison.
    - Correspondence
      - B, N, Z (9), 1917 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Glison, George L. (Lloyd C. Glison) (20), 1917 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Glison, M. L. (1), 1917 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Potter, Owen L. (2), 1917 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Legal papers, 1917 April-Aug, undated (Box 23, Folder 8-10)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - The God of Vengeance
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Harry Weinberger et al., 1923-1925.
    In January of 1923, Weinberger took over as manager of a production of Shalom Asch's The God of Vengeance. The play had been performed in German and Yiddish in New York for the past ten years without interference. In March 1923, however, Weinberger and the entire cast were charged with presenting an "obscene, indecent, immoral or impure drama, play, exhibition, show, or entertainment which would tend to the corruption of the morals of youth or others." Weinberger acted as attorney for the accused. They were convicted, but the decision was ultimately reversed on appeal.